<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<interfaces>
    <quest name="Galann's Revenge">
        <interface npc="Galann Strongfist" state="completed">
            <dialog name="hello">
                <message>Thank you for bringing that stone giant to justice. I can now sleep peacefully at night, knowing that the stone giant will never trouble anyone ever again...</message>
            </dialog>
        </interface>

        <part uid="kill_torathog" name="Enemy of the Past">
            <message>Galann Strongfist, the old smith of Brynknot has asked you to go to the Old Outpost north of Aris in the Giant Mountains and kill Torathog the stone giant in revenge.</message>
            <kill nrof="1" />

            <interface npc="Galann Strongfist" state="need_start">
                <dialog name="hello">
                    <message>Hello there, {activator.name}. I'm {npc.name}, the old smith of Brynknot.</message>
                    <message>If you need services, I suggest you go speak to my son, Conbran Strongfist, southwest from the Main Square. He is the owner of the family's shop now, ever since I was hurt in this fight many years ago...</message>
                    <message>I also hear there are superb smiths in Asteria and Greyton.</message>
                    <response message="Tell me more about the fight..." destination="tellmore" />
                </dialog>
                <dialog name="tellmore">
                    <message>Ah, well, you see, many years ago, while I was still young, I used to adventure now and again. However, one day, while taking a stroll in the Giant Mountains, one of the stone giants living nearby ambushed me! I was hurt badly that day, and only just managed to survive. However, one of my arms was too badly damaged, and since then I haven't been able to do most of the work as a smith...</message>
                    <response message="Tell me more about this stone giant." destination="tellgiant" />
                </dialog>
                <dialog name="tellgiant">
                    <message>He must have been one of the stone giants from Old Outpost, which is nearby from where I was when he ambushed me... His name was Torathog, since he kept yelling at me, saying things like 'Torathog will eat ya!'.</message>
                    <message>In fact, I have heard that this same stone giant was seen just recently near Old Outpost, trying to ambush a party of brave adventurers. Unfortunately, the adventurers did not manage to finish off the giant, as he ran away and hid somewhere, likely in Old Outpost...</message>
                    <response message="I could go and look for him, if you want." destination="lookfor" />
                    <response message="Goodbye." action="close" />
                </dialog>
                <dialog name="lookfor">
                    <message>You would? That sounds dangerous! But I would be very glad if this stone giant was brought to justice... Very well... Old Outpost is at the peak of Giant Mountains, which are north of Aris. If you manage to find Torathog, please bring him to justice.</message>
                    <action start="kill_torathog" />
                </dialog>
            </interface>

            <interface npc="Galann Strongfist" state="need_finish">
                <dialog name="hello">
                    <message>Have you managed to find Torathog yet? He's likely hiding in the Old Outpost, at the peak of Giant Mountains...</message>
                    <response message="Not yet." action="close" />
                </dialog>
            </interface>

            <interface npc="Galann Strongfist" state="need_complete">
                <dialog name="hello">
                    <message>Have you managed to find Torathog yet? He's likely hiding in the Old Outpost, at the peak of Giant Mountains...</message>
                    <response message="He has been taken care of." destination="takencare" />
                </dialog>
                <dialog name="takencare">
                    <message>Indeed? Thank you, {activator.name}. I'm glad he has been brought to justice, after all these years.</message>
                    <message>Here, take this ring. My days of adventuring have been over for a long time now, and I'm sure you can put the ring to better use on your journeys than I could.</message>
                    <item arch="ring_prayers" />
                    <action complete="kill_torathog" />
                </dialog>
            </interface>
        </part>
    </quest>
</interfaces>
