<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<interfaces>
    <quest name="Melanye's Lost Walking Stick">
        <interface npc="Melanye" state="completed">
            <dialog name="hello">
                <message>Thank you for recovering my walking stick and teaching that evil treant a lesson!</message>
            </dialog>
        </interface>

        <part uid="get_stick" name="The Stick">
            <info>Melanye in Brynknot Tavern has asked you to bring her back her walking stick, which was stolen in the middle of the night by some evil treant, waking up the old woman, who saw the evil treant running to the east...</info>
            <item arch="melanye_walking_stick" name="Melanye's Walking Stick" />

            <interface npc="Melanye" state="need_start">
                <dialog name="hello">
                    <message>Well, hello there my dear. Say -- have you seen any evil treants around the place?</message>
                    <response message="Why are you asking?" destination="whyasking" />
                </dialog>
                <dialog name="whyasking">
                    <message>I was asleep just last night, when a treant broke into my room here at the tavern, through the window!</message>
                    <response message="How did you know it was a treant?" destination="howknow" />
                </dialog>
                <dialog name="howknow">
                    <message>Well, it woke me up! I only saw an evil-looking treant running away, holding my enchanted walking stick!</message>
                    <response message="Your enchanted walking stick?" destination="walkingstick" />
                </dialog>
                <dialog name="walkingstick">
                    <message>My walking stick has been enchanted to give off a soft glow wherever it goes. That is how I saw that it was a treant, running off to the east. I'm not sure what use a walking stick is to a treant, but maybe it just liked the soft glow... But now I have to use an ordinary walking stick... Say, would you look for this treant and recover my walking stick? I might have something in return for your troubles...</message>
                    <response message="Sure..." destination="sure" />
                </dialog>
                <dialog name="sure">
                    <message>Why, thank you! I'm sure a strong-looking adventurer like yourself will be able to sort this out in no time at all. Just head east of Brynknot -- that is where the treant ran off to...</message>
                    <action start="get_stick" />
                </dialog>
            </interface>

            <interface npc="Melanye" state="need_finish">
                <dialog name="hello">
                    <message>Have you recovered my walking stick yet? I'm sure the evil treant ran off to the east of Brynknot...</message>
                    <response message="Working on it." action="close" />
                </dialog>
            </interface>

            <interface npc="Melanye" state="need_complete">
                <dialog name="hello">
                    <message>Have you recovered my walking stick yet? I'm sure the evil treant ran off to the east of Brynknot...</message>
                    <response message="Here it is." destination="hereis" />
                </dialog>
                <dialog name="hereis">
                    <message>Oh, you found it! Thank you, thank you...</message>
                    <message>Here, it's all I can spare... I hope it will be useful to you.</message>
                    <item arch="silvercoin" />
                    <action complete="get_stick" />
                </dialog>
            </interface>
        </part>
    </quest>
</interfaces>
